# SHRUTHY SREEPATHY

Dallas, TX - 75252 · +13302348056 · shruthys6@gmail.com · shruthy.com

## **UX Researcher and Designer**

I have 4 years of professional experience in software development and UX design. I'm looking for a full-time position where I can utilize my user research and design skills to improve user experience of the product and bring in customer satisfaction.

#### **EDUCATION**

M.S – Human Computer Interaction | 3.9 GPA | University of Texas at Dallas | Class of May 2018 (expected) B.E – Computer Science Engineering | 81.56% | Bangalore University | Class of Jun 2014

## **EXPERIENCE**

### JUNIOR DESIGNER, ArtSciLab | Sept 2016 - Present

I lead usability testing for an e-book resource website ARTECA; analyze usage pattern using Google Analytics and develop the website in Drupal. I designed prototypes for video channel page; conducted user research workshops to discover issues with search feature and register function.

## UX DESIGNER INTERN, Sabre Corporation | May 2017 - Aug 2017

I conducted usability testing for hospitality check-in workflow; identified usability issues with flight booking flow; practiced KJ method; I worked with UX experts to conduct ethnography, business origami workshop with two fortune 500 clients to understand their target user and build persona.

*Intern case competition finalist* – I designed a mobile app to manage traveler itinerary and my research was an added value that helped us to be one of the top 5 teams.

#### ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER, SAP Labs India Pvt Ltd | Jul 2014 - Jun 2016

I led design thinking process within my team; validated SAP Gateway for Microsoft (GWM) to meet usability & accessibility standards; developed new features & Wizard UI for GWM using C# and WPF in Visual Studio; developed workflow request application for Microsoft Office365 using HTML, CSS and C#

## **SKILLS**

- Usability Testing, Noldus Face Reader
- User Research, persona, empathy map, ethnography, journey map, storyboard, Business Origami, KJ Method
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SAP HANA, C#, ReactJS, REST API
- Interaction design, Information Architecture, visual design
- Agile Methods, Sprint, Scrum
- Rapid prototyping, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Affinity Designer, Axure, InVision, Marvel, UI Toolkit
- JAWS, NVDA Tool, Morae, Validately
- Psychology, OptimalWorkshop

#### **PROJECTS**

**FoodBud** - Designed an interactive app that recommends recipes to users based on ingredients available in their inventory. User research conducted to explore problem - online survey, contextual inquiry, empathy map; define problem - affinity diagramming, persona, user journey map; design - prototypes; test - usability test

**Yahoo Fantasy Football Re-Design -** Re-designed the fantasy football page to make it comply to 12 out of 21 design principles violation. Design process – design critique, ideate, high fidelity prototypes

**Gmail Evaluation** - Conducted heuristic evaluation for Gmail web app, re-designed Gmail homepage and conducted usability testing with 3 participants to validate the new design

**BookBasket** - A library website, developed using HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, which enabled users to logon to their library account, search for books, rent and return books.

#### **OTHER ACTIVITIES**

- Active member of UTD UX Club
- I volunteered and made sketchnotes during Big Design Conference 2016 and 2017
- Presented <u>ArtSide</u> at <u>a2ru</u> conference in 2017 and hosted a <u>design workshop</u> at RAW conference 2018
- At Adobe creative jam 2017, I won first place Judge's Choice Award for iSHY UX design theme "The new normal"